翻译/精修：台译/Xander
仅供学习交流，请于24小时内删除
主世界
The Overworld,
全宇宙最大的沙盒
the biggest sandbox in the universe,
充满了史诗般的故事
is full of epic tales.
精彩纷呈，超乎你的想象
Millions and billions of them.
（地形加载中...）
接下来
Well, guess what?
就是专属于我的冒险故事
This one is all mine.
（儿童严禁入内）
我是史蒂夫
My name is Steve.
从小就一心向往挖矿
And as a child, I yearned for the mines.
可惜一直没能如愿
But it didn't really work out.
滚开，离这里远一点
Go on! Get out of here!
-妈妈 -于是我做了一件可怕的事情
-Mommy! - So, I did a terrible thing.
快滚，走开
Go on! Shoo!
我长大了
- I grew up. - Run!
对，这就是我
Yep, that's me.
一样的衬衫，一样的裤子
Same shirt, same pants.
唯一缺少的就是我的灵魂
The only thing missing, was my soul.
（史蒂夫）
这样的生活究竟有什么意义？
-What was I doing with my life? -
我可不想一直就做门把手销售
I wasn't meant to sell doorknobs.
然后有一天，我想到了什么
And then one day, I remembered something!
没错
That's right!
矿井
The mines!
所以我准备好工具，打算深入挖掘
So I geared up to dig deeper
找回属于我的人生意义
and find out what I'd been missing.
这一次，谁也别想阻止我
And this time, I was unstoppable.
假动作，哦耶
Head fake! Oh, yeah.
我的梦想终于实现了
-My moment had finally come. -Yeah.
我能感受到冒险的气息
I could just taste the adventure!
于是我不知疲倦地疯狂挖矿
So, I mined my brains out.
直到挖到了两个神秘的物体
Until I found two mysterious artifacts.
这个东西
This thingy…
还有那个酷东西
-And that cool thingy. -Ohhh…
当我把这两个玩意儿拼在一起…
And when I put those two thingies together…
不出所料
-…you guessed it. -
就打开了通往另一个世界的传送门
It opened a portal to another world.
主世界
The Overworld!
这个地方让我大开眼界
This place blew my mind.
我从未见过如此奇妙的世界
I'd never seen anything like it.
哇哦
Whoa!
原来这就是我穷极一生都在追寻的地方
Turns out it was the place I'd been looking for my whole life.
在这个世界，你想象到什么
A world where anything you can imagine,
就可以创造什么
you can create!
这是我的第一间房子
This is my first house.
我的第二间房子
-My second house.
我的第三间房子，全羊毛建成
And my third house, made entirely of sheep's wool.
小粉屋
Pink house!
生活很美好
Life was good.
除了每20分钟就会降临的夜晚
Except at night, which happens about every 20 minutes.
这时候我多希望有个朋友陪伴
It was times like these I wished I had a friend.
然后我听到了，友情的嚎叫
And then I heard it. The howl of companionship.
其实是一只想吃掉我的狼
Actually, it was a wolf that wanted to eat me.
我用一根嘎嘣脆的骨头驯服了他
So I tamed him with a crusty femur bone.
-来根骨头？ -没错
-Maybe a bone, huh? -Yeah.
好小子
Attaboy…
丹尼斯
…Dennis.
他超喜欢被挠鼻子
He like a scratchy-scratch on the nariz.
丹尼斯，真乖
Dennis, yeah.
丹尼斯和我形影不离
Dennis and I were inseparable.
我们做什么事都要在一起
We did everything together.
我们建造了无数杰作
We built endless masterpieces.
到后来，我已经是建筑大师了
The more I built, the better I got.
丹尼斯，快来看
Dennis, check it out!
欢迎来到史蒂夫的世界
♪ Welcome to Steve's ♪
（史蒂夫的世界）
哦耶
Ohh! Yeah!
♪Let me tell you♪
♪ 我感到鲜活 ♪
我真幸运，熊猫喜欢派对
Lucky for me, pandas love to party.
奶牛也是
And cows.
♪Let me tell you♪
♪ 我感到鲜活 ♪
我的生活非常完美
-Life was perfect.
时光飞逝
And the years simply flew by.
直到一天，我偶然发现了一座奇怪的废墟
Until one day, I came across some strange ruins.
旁边还刚好有个箱子
And a conveniently placed chest.
打火石
Flint and steel.
哇塞
Whoa!
丹尼斯
Dennis!
别去，丹尼斯
No, Dennis.
结果我们打开了通往全新维度的传送门
Turns out we'd just opened a portal to a totally new dimension.
下界
The Nether.
那里毫无欢乐，毫无创造力
There was no joy or creativity at all.
只有对黄金的极度渴求
-Just a mindless lust for gold.
丹尼斯
Dennis!
这些猪灵蛮兵已经把这个维度摧毁殆尽
These piglin brutes had mined this realm into oblivion,
它们领头的是马戈尔莎
led by Malgosha,
邪恶的猪灵女巫
the evil piglin sorceress who ruled the place.
你是谁，怎么长得圆了咕咚的
Who are you, and why are you so round?
把狗放了，抓我吧
Leave the dog! Take me instead.
不用了，你们两个谁也跑不了
No, thanks. I'll take both of you.
还有那颗球
And that Orb.
咱们先说清楚
Let's get one thing straight.
在我们那，我们管这叫方块
Where I come from, we call this a cube.
抓住他们
Seize them!
玛尔戈莎终于得到了她一直想要的东西
Malgosha had finally got what she'd always wanted,
支配之球
-the Orb of Dominance.
[支配之球]在《我的世界：传奇》中提到，支配之球
拥有腐化信标的能力，使其变为永夜信标。永夜信标
会腐化天空中的太阳，增强猪灵.
整个宇宙中最强大的方块球体
The most powerful cube-shaped orb in the entire universe.
听好，猪灵们
Listen up, you pigs!
有了这颗球，我就能掠夺主世界
With this Orb, I will pillage the Overworld,
那里所有的黄金都将归我们所有
and all its gold will be ours!
我不能让这种事发生
I couldn't let this happen.
主世界救了我
The Overworld had saved me,
现在我得设法拯救它
and now I had to try to save it.
我们要阻止她，丹尼斯
We have to stop her, Dennis.
我们逃走了
So we escaped!
偷回了支配之球
And stole back the Orb!
圆脑袋逃走了
The Roundling got away!
找到他，把那颗球给我带回来
Find him and bring me that Orb!
赶快，丹尼斯，把球带回地球
Hurry, Dennis. Take this to Earth.
跟着我的气味去冬青树街149号
Follow my scent to 149 Holly Oak Drive.
狗狗，记住了吗？
You got that, boy?
好狗狗
Good boy.
这个世界就靠你了
You're the last hope for this world.
快跑，去吧，孩子
-Now, run! Go, boy!
快跑，小毛块
Run, fluff nugget!
你行的，丹尼斯，我爱你
You got this, Dennis, I love you!
快跑
Run!
放开我
Get off of me!
那天丹尼斯成了英雄
Dennis was a hero that day.
他像风一样疾驰
He ran like the wind.
我不知道还能不能再见到他
I didn't know if I'd ever see him again,
但我们得拯救这个世界
but we had a world to save.
他一路跑回我地球的家
So he ran all the way back to my house on Earth
将世间最强大的宝物
and hid the most powerful object in existence
藏到了我的水床下
under my waterbed.
只要支配之球不被发现
As long as the Orb stays hidden,
主世界就是安全的
the Overworld will be safe.
（我的世界大电影）
等会，藏在我的水床下是个馊主意
Wait a second. Putting it under my waterbed's a horrible plan.
（游戏主世界）
（买卖与换购）
（电玩配件）
（1989年世界冠军 中西部资格赛）
噢耶
Yeah.
20世纪80年代末
In the late 1980s,
加雷特·加里森在游戏界掀起了一场风暴
Garrett Garrison took the gaming world by storm…
在热门街机游戏《猛男城市狂暴战》
…becoming the undisputed champion of the hit arcade game,
世界大奖赛中夺得冠军
Hunk City Rampage.
（世界冠军，1989年）
Yeah~
Yeah!
他对这款双人合作游戏的精通
His mastery of this two player co-op
震撼了全世界
shocked the world.
（猛男城市狂暴战）
他在游戏中巧妙运用垃圾投掷技能
His effective use of the garbage toss move
赢得了“垃圾侠”的称号
earned him the nickname, "The Garbage Man."
很快他就
Pretty soon, he became
成为了游戏界的新宠
the envy of the gaming world
还拿下了时时乐餐厅
after landing a lucrative deal
的代言合约
with Sizzler.
Yeah~
-Yeah!
帅爆了，宝贝
Yeah, baby!
垃圾侠
Garbage Man!
帅爆了，宝贝
Yeah, baby!
无庸置疑
One thing's for sure…
Yeah~
Yeah!
这小子所向无敌
…this kid had it all.
-好耶 -该扔垃圾了
-Yeah! -Time to take out the trash.
Yeah~
Yeah!
“垃圾侠”加雷特·加里森？
Garrett "The Garbage Man" Garrison?
抱歉不能签名
No autographs.
祝你有美好的一天
Have a nice day.
（驱逐通知）
帅哦，超酷的
Whoo! Yeah! Super cool!
加雷特“垃圾侠”
Garrett "The Garbage Man."
你能光临，我真是荣幸至极
To what do we owe this pleasure?
少客套了
Pleasure?
你以为我是来这玩的吗
Think I come to storage auctions for fun?
我是生意人，达里尔
I'm a businessman, Daryl.
投资者
An investor.
好的，那我就给你添把火吧
Well, I'm about to shovel some coal into your choo-choo train.
这批拍卖正合你意
You're gonna love this next unit.
有水床
It's got a waterbed.
有几把镐子
It's got some pickaxes.
有一大罐混合坚果
It's got a huge can of mixed nuts.
有一堆中性蓝绿色衬衫
It's got an array of unisex turquoise blouses.
听起来没好货
That sounds terrible.
还有1978年雅达利宇宙机
I think it's also got a 1978 Atari Cosmos.
真假，1978年雅达利宇宙机？
Whoa, whoa, whoa. 1978 Atari Cosmos?
上面是这么写的
That's what it says here.
那种玩意超值钱的
Those things are worth a frickin' fortune.
可不是嘛
Heck yeah they are.
兄弟，如果你能帮我搞定
Bro, if you make this happen for me,
我真的会郑重考虑跟你混
I will strongly consider hanging out with you.
-当真吗，兄弟？ -当然
-You serious, bro? -Yep.
两个肌肉男在路上溜达
Two big buffaloes like us out there, in the wild,
穿着中性蓝绿色衬衫
wearing unisex turquoise blouses.
天呐，那场面绝对劲爆
Oh, boy, that's gonna cause a commotion.
姑娘们准得看傻眼
The ladies aren't gonna know what--
听着，只要你能把落槌价压低在百元以下
Listen, if you could keep the hammer price under a hundy,
我会让你梦想成真
I'll make all your weird fanboy dreams come true.
好吗？
Okay?
两个穿着蓝绿色衬衫的肌肉男
Two loose cannons, wearing turquoise blouses.
就这么办
Yeah. Let's do it.
（宇宙机）
有人出500美元，出价500美元
And we got 500 dollars, 500 dollars over here.
目前500美元，有人出600美元吗？
We got 500 dollars. We got six, do we have six?
有没有人出600美元？目前600美元
Do we have 600 dollars? We got 600 dollars over here.
出价700美元，目前700美元
I'll go over here, 700 dollars, we got 700 dollars.
还是700美元，有人出800美元吗
We got 700 dollars here. We got 800 dollars over here.
有人出850美元，有人出850美元吗？有人出850美元
We got 850. Do we hear 850? Do we-- 850 over here.
还有人出价吗？有人出900美元吗？
Do we hear any more? Do we hear 900? 900?
900美元一次，900美元两次
Nine hundred, going once, 900 going twice.
900美元三次
And 900 going three times.
由本地英雄
And sold to hometown hero,
加雷特·“垃圾侠”·加里森900美元成交
Garrett "The Garbage Man" Garrison, for 900 dollars.
这张支票半年内最好别急着兑
I wouldn't cash that for about six months.
什么？
What?
我的宝贝，雅达利宇宙
Come to papa! Cosmos!
达里尔，游戏机呢？
Daryl? Where is it?
抱歉，我没打开盒子看
I'm sorry. I didn't check the box.
-别激动 -雅达利呢？
-Whoa, whoa, whoa… - Where's the Atari?
-冷静 -这里没有雅达利
-Whoa! -There's no Atari in here!
那你也不能破坏拍卖品
That does not mean you can trash this unit!
我完蛋了老兄, 我...
I'm up against it, man, I'm--
惨了，我的店
Oh, no. My store.
我已经不比当年了
My wrists aren't what they used to be.
我实在…
I just…
我需要个翻身的机会
I need a win, man. I need…
我需要赢一次
I need a win.
我劝你还是别在拍卖会寻宝了
When are you gonna stop looking for treasure inside a storage unit…
你要看清真正的宝藏
and recognize that the real treasure…
就在你的心里
…is inside your heart?
大家散了吧
Let's roll, everyone.
他不尊重其他拍卖的同好
This man has no respect for the storage community.
达里尔
Daryl.
老天
Oh, man.
（89年玩家）
哦不
Oh, no!
老天
Oh, man!
搞什么
What the frick?
听着，查格拉斯也不是我的第一选择
Look, Chuglass was not my first choice either,
但这是妈妈临终时的心愿，她希望我们能安顿下来
but it was Mom's dying wish for us to live here.
起码我是这样觉得
Or at least that's how I interpreted it.
我上网查过
Yeah, I read something online.
这地方挺烂的
This place sucks.
反正租金超低，而且我能有一份全职工作
Anyways, rent is super low, and I've got a full-time gig here,
所以我们也没什么其他办法了
so it's not really an offer we can turn down right now.
是啊，我懂
Yeah, I get it.
听着，你会喜欢上这里的
Look, I think you're really gonna like it here.
那个家伙发什么疯呢
What's going on with that dude?
我的天，亨利，我们到查格拉斯了
Oh my gosh, Henry, we're in Chuglass.
跟薯片查哥打个招呼
Say hi to Chuggy the Chip.
（爱达荷州查格拉斯，美国薯片之都）
（游戏主世界）
（自助搬家公司）
好，新邻居
All right. This is the new neighborhood.
这房子年份有多久远了
When was this house built?
很开心见到你们
It's so nice to meet you.
你好，很高兴见到你
Yeah, nice to meet you.
这是你新老板送来的礼物
Uh, your new bosses sent you this.
大家都喜欢在薯片厂工作
Yeah, people love working at the potato chip factory.
是啊，我负责他们的社交媒体运营
Yeah, well, I'm, uh, I'm running their socials for a little bit.
跟老板夸下海口说能把粉丝数冲到75以上
I said I'd get their follower count past 75.
不错哎
Nice!
你是亨利吧，幸会，我是道恩
You must be Henry. Nice to meet you. I'm Dawn.
你的车上怎么会有羊驼？
Hi. Why is there an alpaca hanging out of your car?
（移动动物园）
我不仅是一名房地产经纪人
Well, real estate's not my only hustle.
还兼职做些移动动物园的活
I also do some mobile zoo stuff on the side.
那我先走了
Anyhoo, I gotta run.
有事给我打电话
Call me if you need anything.
对了，关于你妈妈的事，我真的很抱歉
Also… I'm really sorry about your mom.
你真的很勇敢
It's really brave what you're doing.
希望你知道这点
I hope you know that.
谢谢
Thank you.
冷静点，伙计，我来了
Chill out, man. I'm coming.
真是的
Golly!
（给娜塔莉，爱你的妈妈）
亨利，早餐好了
Henry, breakfast is ready.
我来了
I'm coming.
快看
Check it out.
我做了妈妈招牌的薯球早餐披萨
I made you Mom's signature Tater Tot breakfast pizza.
你在学校的第一天就可以分给同学吃了
So you can hand out slices on your first day.
你不是说要让我正常一点嘛
I thought you wanted me to seem normal.
是啊
I do.
我只是想帮你
I'm just trying to help you out.
我还帮你买了体香喷雾
I got you some body spray.
专属香气很重要
Signature scents are huge here.
“丝绒恶搞”味？
Velvet Mischief?
喷到空气中再走过去
You're gonna want to spray it and then walk into it.
别直接喷身上，味道太重
Don't be too direct. It's really powerful.
-好 -爱你
-Okay. -Love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
闻起来像香蕉面包掺了便便
Smells like banana bread and poo.
（游戏主世界）
（激光瞄准镜，不含游戏卡带）
-你的店好酷 -当然啦
- Your store's really cool. - Yeah, I know.
在找什么吗？
Looking for anything in particular?
没，我就随便看看
Nah, just checking some stuff out.
佛系发言，典型的失败者思维
Non-committal. Classic loser mentality.
我能帮你
I can help.
（人生赢家私教课，垃圾侠加雷特）
刚开了个人生赢家私教课
I'm starting a mentorship program
专治各种不服
for people who want to win at the game of life.
每小时50美元 -酷哦
-Fifty bucks an hour. -Cool.
所以到底怎么才能成为人生赢家？
How do you actually win at life?
这答案值钱着呢，想知道就报课吧
That's literally the answer I charge money for.
薯球，很另类的早餐披萨
Tots. What's with the breakfast pizza?
我姐做的
My sister made it.
我得在学校分着吃，好交朋友
I'm supposed to hand out slices at school to make friends.
第一天就这么急？
A little desperate for day one, don't you think?
我还注意到你喷了“丝绒恶搞”
I also notice that you're wearing Velvet Mischief.
最顶级的香水
It's a wonderful cologne.
每个年轻人都需要一款自己的专属香气
And I strongly believe that every young man should have his own signature scent.
我应该没喷太多吧
I didn't think I applied very much.
听着，给你句金玉良言
Listen, I'm gonna give you a hot Garbage tip.
友情就像拼图
Friendship is like a puzzle.
有时你以为要凑齐全部才够酷
Sometimes you think you need lots of pieces to be cool.
有时其实一片就够了
And sometimes it's just one piece to be cool.
这时别人会说，这哪是拼图，这是张图
And people will be like, "That's not a puzzle, that's a picture."
他们倒也没说错
And they have a right to speak, too.
还有什么问题吗？
Any questions?
还挺多的
Yeah. Quite a few, actually.
听着小子，重点是，团队虽强但其中弱
Listen, kid. The point is, there's no "I" in team.
成为赢家，才能通吃
But there are two in winning.
好吧，我得去学校了
Okay, well, I gotta go to school.
随你便，书呆子，把披萨留下就行
Whatever, nerd. Just leave the pizza.
（查格拉斯中学）
好啦，把名牌戴上吧
All right. Let's put this nametag on.
（你好，我是亨利！）
为什么后面有个感叹号？
Uh, why does it have an exclamation point?
哦，亨利，你能来我们太高兴了
Oh, Henry, we're just so thrilled to have you.
你知道吗，自从那篇学校排名的文章出来后
You know, you're the first student to enroll here,
你是第一个来这报名的学生
ever since that article came out about the school rankings.
不管怎样，我是副校长玛琳，向来是有啥说啥
Anyway, I'm Vice Principal Marlene, and I'm an open book.
你可能已经听说了，我丈夫克莱门特跟我离婚了
You probably heard that my husband, Clemente, recently divorced me.
说实话，这伤痛比预想中轻多了
And to be honest, I expected it to hurt more than it does.
毕竟我们的婚姻之火20年前就熄灭了
You know, the fire went out on our marriage 20 years ago,
硬撑到现在全是为了狗狗们
but we stuck it out for the dogs.
好了，带你去第一节课吧
Okay, let's get you to your first class.
早安
Good morning.
自我介绍一下
Just a little something about myself.
我教体育、美术
I teach gym, I teach art.
我经济拮据的不行
Financially, I'm living in a nightmare, okay?
把我的生活送给仇人我都嫌缺德
I wouldn't wish my life on my worst enemy.
去年我靠退税的4000美元过活
Last year, I claimed 4,000 dollars on my tax return.
暑假我在机场旁卖蛤蜊和生蚝
So in the summer, I do clams and oysters down by the airport.
但我的钱大多花在商场的无人机摊位了
But most of my money is tied up in a drone kiosk at the mall.
好了，今天我们要画静物
Okay, today we're gonna do a still life.
一个橙子，一根香蕉
One orange, one banana.
都动笔吧各位
Let's get after it, people.
（静物，香蕉与橙子）
这是什么？
What is this?
你不懂什么是静物画吗？
Don't you know what a still life is?
就是照着实物画啊
It means you just draw the thing.
下次按照要求来
Do the assignment next time.
你这喷气背包根本飞不起来
That jetpack would never work.
其实没问题的，纯数学计算
It's kind of foolproof, actually. It's just math.
我爸说数学早就被证伪了
My dad said math has been debunked.
瞧瞧，新来的家伙还以为自己是火箭科学家呢
Check it out. New kid thinks he's a rocket scientist.
我确实想当火箭科学家
I'd love to be a rocket scientist.
那就证明给我看
So prove it.
好了，大家一起倒数
All right. Count us down, guys.
5、4、3、2、1
Five, four, three, two, one!
我知道大家都很期待这次的品牌焕新
Okay, so I know that we're all very excited about the new rebrand,
但我认为把派对礼包叫做咸盐福袋实在是不太合适
but I don't think you should call your party bags, "Salt Sacks."
（更多新产品！查格拉斯薯片）
查哥！
Chuggy!
完了
Oh, no!
当我没来过
I was never here, okay?
好消息是，没人死掉
Well, the good news is nobody died.
对不起，这是个意外
I'm sorry, okay? It was an accident.
这足以让你被开除了，亨利
This could be grounds for expulsion, Henry.
你得给监护人打个电话
I need you to call your guardian.
（娜塔莉）
这里是游戏主世界
Game Over World.
垃圾侠先生，我是亨利
Hey, uh, Mr. Garbage Man, it's Henry.
就是带着薯球早餐披萨的那个
The kid with the Tater Tot breakfast pizza?
是你啊
Oh, yeah.
我有事求你帮忙
I have a weird favor to ask.
你能假装我叔叔来趟学校吗
Uh, could you come to my school and pretend to be my uncle?
没门，我不干这种事了
No way. I don't do that stuff anymore.
我出26美元
I have 26 bucks.
你好，我是亨利的叔叔
Hi, I'm Henry's uncle.
你吗？
You?
那个“破烂人”？
The Trash Bag?
是“垃圾侠”
It's actually "Garbage Man."
垃圾侠啊
Garbage Man, huh?
你可以随时把我打包带走
You can bag me up and take me to the curb anytime.
但记得绑紧点，我的爱火可关不住
But you gotta bungee the lid 'cause I got a lot of raccoons in there.
跟你离婚的人真是亏大了
Whoever divorced you is a complete idiot.
我搞不懂，照理说会成功的
I just don't get it. It should have worked.
我没算错
The math is right.
我可能害我姐姐丢了工作
But I probably just cost my sister her job.
哦哇
Oh, wow.
你真的很有创意
You're super creative.
既然你要去少管所了，介意把这张传单还给我吗
Hey, since you're going to juvie, you mind if I get this flyer back?
纸可不是树上长的
Paper don't grow on trees, and…
我也没多少钱去印了
not really allowed in Kinko's anymore.
我的笔记本你也拿走吧
Well, you can have my book, too.
我不要了
'Cause I'm done with it.
这破玩意儿是啥？
So what's this stupid junk?
没研究过
Who cares?
可能是什么高科技骗人玩意
Probably some new age bullcrap.
我可以950美元卖你
I could let it go for like 950.
这玩意能干嘛
I wonder what it does.
有张说明书
Hey. Instructions.
在任何情况下都不要将球体和水晶拼在一起
"Never, under any circumstances, combine the Orb and Crystal."
等等
Uh, wait…
不要跟着球走
"Do not follow this Orb,
即使你是个缺钱的老板，需要大笔资金
even if you're a struggling business owner and need a ton of cash fast
因为这里有一堆宝藏
because there's loads of treasure down here."
嘿 老哥 老哥? 它好像要去某个地方
Hey, dude. Dude? It feels like it wants to go somewhere.
什么？
What?
抱歉，我都试过了，不知道还能找谁帮忙
I'm sorry. I tried everything. I didn't know who else to call.
没关系的，出什么事了？
No, it's okay. What's going on?
亨利不见了
Henry's missing. I tried the school.
我给学校打过电话了，他的手机我也打了无数次
I tried his phone a million times.
他都不接，他几个小时前就应该到家了
He's not answering. He was supposed to be home hours ago.
我还以为他因为炸了薯片查哥被罚留校了呢
I thought he'd still be in detention for blowing up Chuggy The Chip.
-是他干的？ -手机给我
-That was him? -Give me your phone.
天哪，真不敢相信
Oh, my gosh. Oh, I can't believe this.
我们才来一天，他就已经是全民公敌了
We're here for one day, and he's already the town villain.
找到他了
Got him!
他没事，只是在废弃矿井里玩呢
He's fine. He's just playing in an abandoned mineshaft.
什么？
What?
走吧，我来开车
Come on. I'll drive.
你来喂羊驼吃胡萝卜
You can feed Mr. Scribbles this busted carrot
如果不想被它咬到的话
if you wanna keep that pretty face of yours.
上车
Hop in.
好吧
Okay.
你先走，我给你断后
You go first. I'll cover your six.
没问题
Yeah, yeah. I got you.
（危险，禁止擅自闯入）
危险吗，不管了
Danger. Whatever.
哇塞
Whoa.
-亨利 -天哪
- Henry! -Oh, gosh!
你来这里干嘛？
What are you doing down here?
这个人是谁？
-Who's this guy? -He's my new mentor.
他是我的新导师
谁？我吗？
Who, me? Oh.
抱歉，你说什么？
I'm sorry. What?
各位，你们看
Hey, guys! Guys!
它在拉我 各位
It's pulling me, guys.
亨利
Oh, Henry!
亨利，放开那个东西
Henry, let go of that thing!
好痛，我的屁股
Oh, man, my butt. My butt.
没错
Yep.
我们已经不在爱达荷州了
We're not in Idaho anymore.
我觉得这是怀俄明州
I think this is Wyoming.
等会，你是谁来着？
Wait, who are you again?
加雷特·“垃圾侠”·加里森 1989年电玩冠军
Garrett "The Garbage Man" Garrison. Gamer of the Year, 1989.
随便了，我都不怎么提的
Whatever. I barely think about it.
这是什么鬼
What the heck?
如果我猜得没错，我们应该是要找他接任务
If that's what I think it is, it could be our first quest giver.
我来跟他聊
I'll do the talking.
你好 你好！
All right, yeah!
-亨利 -慢点，亨利
- Henry! - Yeah, Henry!
别跟他乱跑
Come on back here.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
听好，猪灵们
Listen up, you swine!
找不到更多黄金
If you can't find more gold,
我就把你们都送到主世界去，让你们僵尸化
I'll just send you to the Overworld to zombify.
你
You!
你在干嘛？
What are you making?
过来点，没事的
Come closer. It's all right.
来吧，我又不咬人
Come on. I'm not gonna bite you.
哎呀，真漂亮
Oh! How pretty.
但这怎么能帮我找到更多的黄金呢
But how will that help me find more gold?
哎呀
Oops.
怎么回事？
What?
瞧瞧是什么东西回来了
Well, looky what we have here.
我们的时机终于来了
Our time has come.
圆脑袋
Roundling!
马戈尔莎
Malgosha!
我是没讲清楚吗？
Was I unclear when I said
不要浪费时间在创造和爱好上
no one was to waste time on art or leisure?
支配之球回来了
The Orb has returned.
不可能
It can't be.
丹尼斯？
Dennis?
是你从我这儿偷走的，现在你得把它拿回来
You stole it from me, and now you will retrieve it.
我的荣幸，女王陛下
It would be a privilege, my liege.
我们现在要给你松绑了
We're going to unbind you now.
别干蠢事
Don't do anything stupid.
当然不会
Of course not.
你可以相信我这个地牢小囚徒的
You can trust this little dungeon pup.
看我偷袭
Let me just-- Sneak attack--
来吧，只要你敢
Go ahead. Strike me down.
我的手下就会吃掉你的宠物小狼
My piglins will make a meal of your beautiful wolf.
我怎么知道你说的是真的？
How do I know you're telling the truth?
你只能乖乖听话
There's only one way to find out.
就去拿到那颗球，来换你小狗的命
The Orb for your little dog's life.
你好，睿智的任务发布者
Hola, wise Quest Giver.
我们诚心诚意地寻求黄金
We humbly seek gold.
发布一个能让我们找到宝藏的任务吧
Give us a quest that will lead us to your treasure load.
垃圾侠，我就是开动物园的，我保证
Garbage Man, I work in the animal field, and I am telling you,
那东西根本听不懂你在说什么
that thing doesn't understand a word you're saying.
我们在交流呢
-We're talking. -
抱歉，你刚才说什么？
Sorry about that. What were you saying?
走吧，亨利，我们回家
Okay. Come on, Henry. We're going home.
这天黑的也太快了点吧？
That feel quick to anyone else?
是啊
Yeah.
好了，各位
All right, everyone.
保持冷静
-Stay calm.
放松
Relaje.
免费的垃圾侠小贴士
Free Garbage tip.
恐惧，是因为软弱在身体里占领了高地
Fear is just weakness hijacking your body's cockpit.
什么鬼？
What in the hell?
如果你害怕
And if that happens,
你就可以跟你的身体的导航系统说再见了
you can say vaya con Dios to your body plane's navigation system.
什么？
What?
垃圾侠的英语和西班牙语都挺烂的
Yeah, Garbage Man isn't speaking English or español.
我在这里干嘛？
What am I doing here?
快逃
Run!
加雷特
Garrett!
对不起，死人可拿不了年度游戏冠军
I'm sorry! Dead dudes can't win Gamer of the Year!
亨利
Henry!
哇哦
Whoa!
-噢! -僵尸朝我们来了
- Oh! -Yo! We got a zombie problem!
我们得马上行动
We need to go right now!
亨利，快点
Henry, come on!
继续，别停下
It's not a good time to stop.
亨利，快点
Henry! Hurry up!
（TNT）
他是怎么做到的？
How's he doing that?
我不知道，但也许有用
I don't know, but it might work.
这边，再快点
This way! Faster!
你行的
You got this.
-加油，亨利 -再快点，再快点
-Go, Henry! -Don't slow down, boy.
加油，加油
Don't you slow down! You can do this!
继续，亨利，赶快啊
Keep going, Henry! Come on, come on! Quickly!
再快点，加油
Faster, faster, faster! Come on!
对不起，我不是故...
Oh, my gosh. I'm so sor--
亨利，拜托 救我，亨利
Henry! Help me, please! Henry!
加雷特，快过来
Garrett! Garrett, over here!
加雷特
Garrett!
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
他们就在你后面
They're right behind you!
-上面 -加雷特，这里
-Up here! - Garrett, over here!
糟了，这下坏了
Oh, no! That can't be good!
你这白痴，快跑
You idiot. Run!
-小心 -边打边跑
- Watch out! - Hit it and run!
开门
Open the door!
走开
Hai! Go away!
快点，把这个方块脑袋的蠢蛋推下去
Come on! Let's push that booger-looking box-head!
老天，好吓人
Oh, man. Oh, boy!
你还在动
Oh! You're movi--
亨利，天啊
Hank! Oh, man.
天啊，不要
Oh, man, no!
♪Let me tell you♪
♪让我告诉你♪
♪Girl! You my lil' boo thang♪
♪女孩，你是我的宝贝♪
♪So, I don't give a hoot what your dude say♪
♪我才不管那个家伙说了啥♪
♪Girl, I know You a lil' too tame♪
♪女孩，你太善良了♪
♪I'll be shooting that shot like 2K♪
♪我爱你的方式一定会让你满意♪
♪Girl, I know Tell 'em I'm, tell 'em I'm next Tell 'em you found a lil' something too fresh ♪
♪告诉他们你已经找到了新的小可爱♪
♪what's good, what's with ya?♪
♪你说呢，如何呀♪
♪If you booked tonight, that's fiction♪
♪预定快乐房间，就像是科幻片♪
♪I'm outside, no pictures♪
♪我就在外面，没有一张照片♪
尝尝这个
Taste it!
♪You want me, go figure♪
♪想要得到我，自己去琢磨♪
♪To the back, to the front You a ten, but I'm the one♪
♪前前后后，我就是真命天子♪
看我偷袭!
-Sneak attack!
♪Girl! You my lil' boo thang♪
♪女孩，你是我的宝贝♪
♪So, I don't give a hoot what your dude say♪
♪我才不管那个家伙说了啥♪
♪Girl, I know You a lil' too tame♪
♪女孩，你太善良了♪
♪I'll be shooting that shot like 2K♪
♪我爱你的方式一定会让你满意♪
♪Girl, I know Tell 'em I'm, tell 'em I'm next Tell 'em you found a lil' something too fresh ♪
♪告诉他们你已经找到了新的小可爱♪
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是…
I…
史蒂夫
…am Steve.
你们是谁？丹尼斯在哪？
Who are you people? Where's Dennis?
丹尼斯？我们不认识什么丹尼斯
Dennis? Who's-- We don't know any Dennis.
那你们哪来的这个东西？
Then how'd you get that?
嘿，放松，这是我的
Hey. Relaje, muchacho. This is my property.
你们知道这是什么吗？
Do you even know what that is?
这个是支配之球
It's the Orb of Dominance.
这是个方块
It's a cube.
行吧
Okay.
你们真的不知道自己在干什么
You people seriously have no idea what you're dealing with.
交出来，没人会受伤
Hand it over and no one gets hurt.
门都没有
No way!
我们需要这个东西才能回家
Okay, we need this thing to get home.
我不愿泼你们冷水
I hate to take a big, fat dumparoo on your plans,
但你们回不了家
but you can't get home.
等等，回不了家是什么意思？
W-W-Wait. What do you mean we can't get home?
没有魔力结晶就免谈
Not without the Earth Crystal.
你是说那个小盒子？垃圾侠把它弄坏了
You mean that little boxy thing? Garbage Man busted it.
别怪我
Nuh-uh.
亨利，你带着这个吧
Listen, Henry, why don't you hold this?
你比他靠谱多了，孩子
You got those good Frodo vibes, kid.
我也很靠谱啊
I got Frodo vibes.
你是说我们被困在这儿了？
Are you implying that we're stuck here?
对
Yes!
除非你们拿到魔力结晶，这是你们回家的唯一办法
Unless you get the Earth Crystal. It's your only way home.
只能去林地府邸
There's only one way you could ever replace it,
找一个新的魔力结晶
at the Woodland Mansion,
但去那里必死无疑
but going there would get you all killed!
留在这里也一样啊
Well, so would staying here.
有道理
Fair enough.
听着，我能带你们回家，但你们得把球给我
Listen, I can get you home, but then you gotta give me that Orb.
你要拿它做什么
So, what are you gonna do with it?
不关你的事
None of your concern!
怎么样，我们达成协议了吗
So, what do you say? Do we have a deal?
他刚才杀了20个僵尸
He did just kill, like, 20 zombies.
顶多15个，不过也行
Pfft! More like 15, but okay.
好吧，史蒂夫
All right, Steve.
有两个条件
Under two conditions.
第一，随时向我报告 因为我才是老大
One, always address me, because I'm the leader.
第二，如果你敢背叛我们
Two, if you double-cross us…
我会用我的屁股把你脑袋像核桃一样挤爆
…I will crack your cabeza with my butt cheeks like a walnut.
这家伙真是让人受不了
This guy is such a toolbag.
真抱歉
- I'm so sorry.
我们也刚刚认识这个人，他也不是老大
We just met this man, and he's not the leader.
好吧，看起来粉红猛男同意我的交易了
Well, it looks like Dr. Swollenstein here just got himself a deal.
天哪
Oh, my God.
好吧
All right.
我们先去弄些装备，不然我们小命不保
First we need to load up on some gear, or we're all gonna die.
咱们去中港村
Let's go to Midport Village.
这家伙真是疯了
This guy's lost his mind.
出发
Move out!
哦不，又撞到了
Oh, no. Not again.
很抱歉
I am so sorry.
天啊，你没事吧？天啊
Oh, my God. Are you all right? Oh, my God.
我的天，你没事吧？
Oh, my God. Are you all right?
你的脑袋好大啊
Your head is huge.
你不会要起诉我吧？
You're not gonna sue me, are you?
因为我一开车撞到人
Because everyone wants to sue me
他们就都起诉我
once I hit them with my Jeep Grand Cherokee.
天啊
-Oh, my.
要不这样，我请你吃顿饭怎么样？
How about this? What if I just take you to dinner?
你愿意和我去吃顿饭吗？
Would you like to go to dinner?
到了，中港村
Here it is. Midport Village.
我有个秘密藏宝屋，里面全是尖端装备
I got a secret stash of elite loot
能帮我们挺过林地府邸
that'll help us survive the Woodland Mansion.
等等，等等，这些人是谁？
Whoa, whoa, whoa, who are these guys?
哦，他们是村民
Oh, these dudes? They're the villagers.
他们既和平又吃素
They're total pacifists and vegetarians.
你不招惹他们，他们也不会招惹你
You don't bug them, they won't bug you.
他们喜欢闲逛、交易，狂吃面包
They just like to chill, trade, and eat buttloads of bread.
他们特别喜欢吃面包
They love crushing loaf.
他们建造了这一切？
So they built all this?
对，大部分都是
Yeah, most of it.
不过好看的建筑，都是我史蒂夫建造的
But the good stuff you see, that's all Steve.
他是个什么国王吗？
Whoa. Is he some kind of king?
此处典故为最受欢迎的《我的世界》主播
Technobladey，外号猪神，创造了“起床战
争”玩法1000连胜，因癌症于2022年6月30
日去世
不是
No.
他是个传奇
That's a legend.
孩子，这里你能想到的任何东西，都能造出来
Kid, anything you can dream about here, you can make.
没有限制，你懂吗
Zero limits. You know what I'm talking about.
- 那是你建造的塔楼，对吧？ - 对
-That was your tower, right? -Yeah.
对于初次尝试来说非常不错了
Pretty killer for a first build.
不用怕，它是铁傀儡
Relax. It's just an Iron Golem.
当地的安保力量
Local security force.
他们都是一群善良的大软蛋
But they're a bunch of big softies!
除非你招惹了村民
Unless you start messing with the villagers.
它才会攻击你
Don't ever do that!
这地方简直毫无逻辑
This place makes no sense.
跟我来
Come with me!
我需要蛋白质，马上
Yo, I need protein, like, pronto.
我刚好知道个地方
I got just the place, buddy.
你好
Hello there.
我刚走近就已经起鸡皮疙瘩了
Oh, dude, I got goose pimples just walking up on it.
你们想没想过鸡肉碰到熔岩会怎样？
You ever wonder what happens when you mix hot lava and chicken?
我想过，你马上就会知道了
I did, and you're about to find out.
听到了吗？
You hear that?
是油花四溅的声音
That's the sound of sizzle-een.
是不是很香
-Smell that smell.
♪熔-熔-熔-熔岩♪
♪ La-la-la-lava ♪
♪鸡-鸡-鸡-烤鸡♪
♪ Ch-ch-ch-chicken ♪
♪史蒂夫的熔岩烤鸡，美味至极♪
♪ Steve's Lava Chicken Yeah, it's tasty as hell ♪
♪噢，妈妈咪呀，现在你正敲响味觉铃铛♪
♪ Ooh, mamacita Now you're ringing the bell ♪
♪酥脆又多汁，现在你正大快朵颐♪
♪ Crispy and juicy Now you're having a snack ♪
♪超级美味，就像被熔岩攻击♪
♪ Ooh, super spicy It's a lava attack! ♪
我也是做生意的
I have a small business too.
但我可不会用这么烂的广告歌
But one thing I try to do is not have my jingle suck butt.
真是丢人
Friggin' loser.
把鸡腿给我
Pass the bird, turkey.
我可不像史蒂夫那样是个胆小鬼
I'm not a little wimp like big Steve here.
我不怕热，不怕痛
I crave heat. And I crave pain.
加雷特，慢点
Garrett, wait!
听我说
Hear my words.
那只鸡刚刚还在滚烫的熔岩里
That chicken was just cooked in hot lava.
你最好放凉再吃
Let it cool down, man.
不错嘛
Not bad.
垃圾侠，你有够白痴的
Garbage Man… you're a big-time idiot.
又怎么了？
What is it?
什么？
What?
查格拉斯将军，给我过来
General Chungus! Get over here.
马尔戈莎，找我啥事啊？
Hey, Malgosha. What's going on?
你地牢里的老朋友史蒂夫背叛了我们
Your old dungeon buddy, Steve, has betrayed us.
哎呀，真糟糕
Well, that's a bummer.
支配之球在四个圆脑袋那里
The Orb is with four Roundlings.
我的密探说，他们在史蒂夫的熔岩烤鸡店
My spies tell me he has taken them to his lava chicken shack.
不会吧，我超爱那间店的
No way. I love that place.
♪熔-熔-熔-熔岩，鸡-鸡-鸡-烤鸡♪
♪ La-la-la-lava Ch-ch-ch-chicken ♪
闭嘴
Shut up!
你马上带兵前去，把那颗球给我夺回来
Take your finest warriors, bring me that Orb,
杀掉那些圆脑袋
and kill the Roundlings.
是要我干掉他们吗？
So, like, you want me to end his life or whatever?
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
你觉得我在说什么
What do you think I'm talking about?
遵命
Okay.
我刚才脑筋没转过来而已
I was just kinda confused there for a second.
带上下界疣，以免被僵尸化
Take this Nether wart so you don't zombify.
大王，我觉得这不够分的
Your Majesty, I don't think this is gonna be enough to go around.
自己解决
Deal with it!
没问题
No worries.
好了，大家喝吧
All right. Drink up, guys.
可别被僵尸化了
You don't wanna zombify up there.
每人只喝一小口
But just tiny sips, okay?
我们该怎么找到那个林地府邸？
Okay, so, how do we find this Woodland Mansion thing?
翻过山，穿过黑森林
Over the mountains, into the dark forest,
就在巨型红色蘑菇后方
right beyond the massive red shrooms.
- 巨型红色蘑菇？ - 超级大的红蘑菇
-Massive red shrooms? -Mm-hm. Big old red ones.
史蒂夫，我们需要张正经的地图
We need to find a real map, Steve.
这里很危险，我得带我弟弟回家
This place is dangerous, and I need to get my brother out of here.
看起来他在这儿挺开心的
Well, it seems like he's having a pretty good time.
听着，你弟弟很有天赋，你知道的，对吧？
Look, your brother has a gift. You know that, right?
你应该让他探索看看
You should let him explore it.
在这个世界里，创造力是生存的关键
Creativity in this world is key to survival.
可在现实世界，善于创造未必是件好事
Okay, well, in the real world, things are a little bit different.
有创造力的孩子在体育课上总被垫底选
Creative kids get picked last for gym,
午餐只能坐在角落，挨欺负
they sit at the bummer lunch table and they get bullied.
我可太懂了
Don't I know it.
你知道他在家里都干嘛了吗？
Do you even realize what he did back home?
他把薯片查哥给炸了
He blew up Chuggy The Chip!
也许我更适合呆在这里
Well, maybe I belong in this world.
亨利，我不是那个意思
Henry, that's not what I meant.
我不是在怪你
That's not what I was saying at all.
你得知道
Just so you know,
我比你更像亨利的姐姐
I'm more of a sister to Hank than you'll ever be.
是不是？
Yeah.
回旋踢
Spin kick.
（史蒂夫的秘密藏宝屋）
-你还好吗？ -没事
-You okay? -Fine.
听着，我找到了一个大脑袋村民在卖地图
Look, I found one of these big-headed-looking dudes that sells maps.
看起来挺靠谱的，来吧
Looks legit. Come on.
欢迎来到我的藏宝屋
Welcome to the stash.
TNT
TNT.
烟花火箭，兼具加速功能
Firework rockets. Also good for propulsion.
迅捷之靴
Boots of Swiftness.
整套钻石盔甲
Diamond armor, full set.
各种各样的剑
And blades for days.
我们去林地府邸所需的一切都在这儿了
Everything we'll need to make it to Woodland Mansion.
好赞
Whoa.
一般般了
Bogus layout, bro.
看就好，别乱碰
Look but don't touch.
这些都是我的珍藏
Those are some of my favorite treasures.
这是什么东西
What's this junk?
那是末影珍珠
That is an Ender Pearl.
丢去哪就能被传送到哪
Teleports you to wherever you throw it.
- 最好是 - 不要!
-Yeah, right. -No!
妈呀
Oh, God.
啥情...
What the…
我就这一个
And that was the only one I had.
没啥大不了
No biggie.
我为了它差点被末影人干掉
Almost died fighting an Enderman for it.
跟我来
Come with me.
这是工作台
This is a crafting table.
是这么用的
Here's how it works.
将这些材料放到不同的方格中
You place these elements in different patterns,
我变
and kaboom!
这样就做出了一把剑
You got yourself a sweet blade.
想看像样的剑吗？
You wanna see a blade?
让我给你开开眼界
I'll show you a blade.
看好了
-Yeah!
锤子给我
Hammer.
我变
Kadoosh!
这也挺好的，这里用得着水桶
That's okay, bud. Buckets are useful here.
很酷啊，加雷特，就像双节棍
Yeah. They're cool, Garrett. They're like nunchucks.
我知道，我是故意这么做的
Yeah, I know. That's why I made them.
这是...双节桶
They're…Buck-Chuckets.
呃...什么？
Uh… they're what?
我能试试吗？
Hey, can I try something else?
当然没问题
Abso-rootin'-tootly.
老弟，你一直带着薯球呢？
Bro, you had Tots the whole time?
对，抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
薯球发射器
It's a Tot Launcher.
你刚把现实世界里不起眼的东西
Dude, you just took boring junk from the real world
拿来创造出了这么棒的东西
to create something amazing.
这简直太厉害了
That is next-level.
亨利？
Hank?
一会能借我玩玩吗？
Can I play with your Tot Launcher when you're done?
-好啊 -太棒了
-Yeah. -Sweet.
史蒂夫，我能跟你聊会儿吗？
Hey, Steve. Can I talk to you for a second?
没问题
Sure thing.
什么事？
What's up?
记得你附在球上的纸条吗？
You know that note you left with the Orb?
写着发财的事？
The one about the riches?
我看了
I read it.
这里到处都是财宝
Yeah. There's riches everywhere.
我在红石矿山就藏了一大堆钻石
I keep a fat stash of diamonds at the Redstone Mines.
这些宝藏是在往林地府邸的路上吗？
So this treasure load, is it on the way to this Mansion place?
不是，要绕一大圈
Not really. It's a major detour.
而且那里很危险
Plus, the mines can be perilous.
我直说好了，史蒂夫
Let me keep it simple for you, Steve.
没有钻石…就没有支配之球
No diamonds, no Orb.
你懂我意思吧？
You smell what I'm steppin' in?
你好
Good day.
我们需要一张去林地府邸的地图
We need a map to the Woodland Mansion.
我们只需要一张地图
We just need a map.
-小娜？ -道恩？
-Nat? -Dawn?
不太对劲
Something's going down.
来吧 朋友们，开始大搞破坏吧
All right, guys, just start trashing their produce.
村民讨厌找碴
Villagers hate that.
这群家伙是谁？
Who are these guys?
猪灵，他们肯定是冲着支配之球来的
Piglins. They must be after the Orb.
史蒂夫，你怎么样呀？
Hey, Steve. What's going on, dude?
可恶，是查格拉斯
Crap! Chungus.
我很抱歉，但马戈尔莎叫我过来杀掉你们
I'm really sorry, but I have to un-alive you and stuff.
马尔戈莎背叛了我
Malgosha double-crossed me.
我们只想要拿那个支配之球
We just need that Orb thingy.
你认识这家伙？
You know this guy?
认识，我们以前一起被关进过地牢
Yeah, we used to get into some dungeon stuff.
他看起来不错，但是个杀手
He seems nice, but he's a killer!
哇，你看起来真不错，兄弟
Wow, you look good, Bro-Hammer.
减肥了吗
You lose some weight?
退后，两位
Stand back, boys.
我来搞定这只猪
This pig is mine.
停
No.
我受够了你总是抢风头
I'm tired of you getting all the glory.
这头猪交给我吧
This pig is mine.
史蒂夫
Steve!
-我们要找到亨利 -好
-We have to get to Henry. -Yeah.
你觉得我们能对付这些家伙吗？
Do you think we could take these guys?
来吧，一起上
Come on, let's do this!
我们可以的
Yeah, we got this!
♪Let me introduce you to your regrets♪
♪让你见识下，你马上就会后悔♪
♪You start messing with me, you won't forget♪
♪要是敢惹我，绝对让你终身难忘♪
♪What you see is not just a pretty face♪
♪我可不只是一张漂亮脸蛋♪
♪I'm about to kick your butt to outer space♪
♪我会把你踢到外太空♪
♪I go from zero to hero♪
♪从零开始，变成大英雄♪
♪You wanna take me on, I turn the pressure up♪
♪你要是想和我较量，我会加大压力♪
好身手，兄弟
Nice moves, bro.
抱歉咯
Sorry.
♪I go from zero to hero♪
♪从零开始，变成大英雄♪
♪You wanna take me on, I turn the pressure up♪
♪你要是想和我较量，我会加大压力♪
好耶
Yes!
♪Higher than Kilimanjaro♪
♪海拔比乞力马扎罗山还要高♪
♪You wanna take me out, come on and try your luck♪
♪要想把我打败，来碰碰运气吧♪
派对结束了
The party's over, bud.
把支配之球交出来
Just give me the Orb.
等一下，我有点事要和你说
Let me tell you something. Let me tell you something!
什么？
What?
哇哦
Whoa!
谢谢你了，大块头
Thanks, big guy.
忍者滚翻
Ninja roll!
发生什么事了？
What happened?
我刚救了你，就是这回事
I just saved your butt, that's what happened.
不必急着谢我
You can thank me later.
我们得去城墙，跟我来
We gotta get to the rampart. Follow me!
亨利！
Henry!
小娜，我们得走了
Nat, we have to go now.
道恩，我不能丢下他 他是我唯一的家人
Dawn, I cannot leave him. He's my entire family.
他需要你活着，好吗？
He needs you alive, okay?
我们可以在林地府邸碰头
We'll meet him back at the Woodland Mansion.
我们得去找卖地图那个人，快来
We gotta go find the map guy! Come on!
跟我来
Follow me!
-加雷特，娜塔莉呢？ -我们去林地府邸跟她碰面
-Garrett, what about Natalie? -We'll meet her at the Mansion.
快点，快跑
Come on, run!
-妈呀 -哇
-Whoa! - Whoa.
是死路，现在怎么办？
Oh, great. Now what?
鞘翅翼装
Elytra Wingsuits!
哇
Whoa!
朝那边的山峰飞
Head for those mountains.
我们不是去林地府邸吗
I thought we're going to the Woodland Mansion.
亨利，大人说话别顶嘴
Hank, don't talk back to your elders.
-可是… -拜拜
-But-Buh -bye.
你确定这玩意能用吧？
Those things work, right?
包的
Absolutely.
快看，我在飞
Check it out. I'm flying!
噢耶
Yeah!
（西班牙语）“早安”
Buenos días.
意思是“待会见”
Which means, "See you later."
不，我以为我有三个的
No! I thought I grabbed three!
等等我
Wait for me!
我来了
Coming in hot!
别抓这么用力
No! No way, dude!
别扯我的头发
Let go of my hair!
放松点，我用屁股给你导航
Just relax. Let my hips guide you.
只能这样了
It's the only way.
什么？
What?
亨利，我们分头行动，这样更有胜算
Hank! We'll have a better chance if we split up!
什么？
-What?
放开我
Get off me!
放开
噢耶
Yeah!
3点钟方向有猪骑士
We got hog riders at our three o'clock!
我抓紧你了，老兄
I got you, buddy!
他们包围我们了
-They got us boxed in!
从洞穿过去
Head for the tunnel!
过不去，我们体积太大了
We're not gonna fit! We're too chunky!
我们要用头对脚体位
We're gonna have to go nose-to-toes.
人肉三明治
Full man sandwich.
什么？我不要
What? No. I'm not gonna do that!
我命令你立即使用人肉三明治
I'm ordering you to make a full man sandwich!
好吧
Okay!
好耶
Yeah!
该死，是熔岩桶
Dang it! A lava bucket!
-好了 抱紧! -什么？
-Okay. Tighten up! -What?
空间还是不够
There's still some negative space back there!
再抱紧一些
We both know it!
我在尽力抱紧了
I'm trying to close the gaps!
好，预备
Okay, now get ready.
我要夹紧屁股保护你了
I'm gonna squeeze for your safety.
我尽量忍住
I understand.
好耶
Yeah!
噢耶
放开我
Get off me!
亨利
Henry!
惨了
Oh, crap.
别担心
Don't worry!
我用落地水来缓冲
I'm gonna cushion our fall with this water bucket.
走你！
Release!
小娜你真能打，简直太厉害了
You can really fight, Nat. You were kicking butt.
谢了，我也不知我这么强
Thanks! I have no idea where it came from.
找到他了
There he is!
回来，我们需要地图
Hey! Get back here! We need a map!
我们需要艘船
First, we need a boat.
我来想办法
Okay, okay, uh…
快点，村民要漂走了
Okay, hurry. The map guy's floating away!
变出船！
Boat magic!
小娜，这是我见过的最糟的船
Nat, that's the worst boat I've ever seen.
抱歉，我没搞懂怎么做
I'm sorry. I have no idea what I'm doing.
别管了，走吧，快来
Forget it. Let's go, come on!
不用了，谢谢
No, thank you.
不客气
Of course.
说真的，我很开心
You know, I gotta tell you, I'm having a great time.
我...呃...我最近和我丈夫克莱门特离婚了
I, uh… I recently got divorced from my husband, Clemente, and…
主要原因是他…
and the main reason is, you know, he…
没有一丝个性
didn't have any personality, you know?
不像你
I mean, not like you.
你得好好解释一下，我和亨利都需要答案
You got some talking to do, buddy. Hank and I want some answers.
比如，我们要怎么阻止那些猪？
Like how are we gonna stop those pigs?
为什么我的胡子有股臭奶酪味？
And why does my beard smell like gorgonzola?
对，还有你说的邪恶女巫是谁？
Yeah, and who's that evil sorceress -you were talking about?
听着
-Look!
女巫是猪灵女王，叫做马戈尔莎
The sorceress is a piglin queen called Malgosha.
那些是她的小啰喽
Those are her minions.
她在一片名为下界的黑暗地狱里统治着它们
She rules over them in a dark hellscape called the Nether.
还有我总是在前口袋里放着块奶酪
And I always keep a chunk of gorgonzola in my front pocket, okay?
听着
Listen!
马戈尔莎的黑化之路没有什么新意
Malgosha's path to darkness started the way these things often do…
那是在“下界达人秀”的半决赛
during the semi-finals of The Nether's Got Talent.
（下界达人秀）
小马戈尔莎一直梦想成为世界级舞蹈大师
Young Malgosha always dreamed of being a world-class dancer.
但她的舞蹈太超前了
Her moves were pretty out there.
超出了观众们的欣赏范围
No one in the Nether was ready for it.
这让她备受打击
It crushed her.
我跟你说过别老是跳舞了吧
What'd I tell you about all that dancing?
你该长大了
It's time for you to grow up.
我受够让你追求梦想了
I'm tired of you chasing your dreams.
拿着镐子，挖黄金去
Now, take this axe and go find some gold.
那舞跳得真丢人
That was such embarrassing dancing!
从那天开始，她就摒弃了所有形式的创造力
So, from that day forward, she denounced all forms of creativity.
如果她拿到那颗球，就会让太阳消失
If she ever gets that Orb, she'll black out the sun.
下界疣会疯长
Nether wart will flourish.
这个美丽世界的里里外外都会凋零殆尽
This beautiful world and everything in it will wither and die.
你居然打算把球给她？
And you were gonna give it to her?
真是个好主意
Great idea!
我才不会给她呢
I'm not gonna give it to her.
但我需要那颗球来作为筹码
But I need that Orb for leverage.
我要救丹尼斯
I gotta save Dennis.
过来
Come.
林地府邸就在红石山脉的后方
The Woodland Mansion is just beyond the Redstone Mountains.
我们可以绕过去，也可以穿过去
We can go over or through.
选比较快的
Whatever's fastest.
穿过去更快
Through will be faster.
查格拉斯将军，这是你最后一次失败了
General Chungus, you have failed me for the last time.
我真的很抱歉
Yeah, I'm really sorry about that.
把怪兽放出来
Bring out the beast!
什么？
What?
没装脑子是什么意思？
What do you mean you just have to put the brain in?
这可是件大事，赶紧办吧
Well, yes, it's a big deal. Get it done!
听着，大家都知道我状态不是很好
Look, everybody knows it wasn't my best day.
但我真的在努力了，下次...
But I'm really trying to set some new goals, and--
霸王猪灵
The Great Hog.
我的终极武器
My ultimate weapon.
他来了
There he is!
杀了他
Kill him!
等等，你的意思是要开除我？
Wait, does this mean you're firing me?
干得好
Well done.
找到圆脑袋，把球给我拿来
Now, find the Roundlings and bring me the Orb!
这下彻底迷路了
We are so lost.
我唯一的任务就是保护亨利，可我却搞砸了
My one job was to protect Henry, and I blew it.
我向妈妈保证过，绝不会让他出事
I just promised my mom I'd never let anything happen to him.
我真不是当家长的料
I guess I'm just not cut out for this parenting stuff.
我还是希望自己当个孩子
I just wish I could have been a kid
可以更久一点 明白吗?
for a little bit longer, you know?
就为了那种觉得自己无所不能的感觉
Just to have that feeling like I could have done anything.
我懂你，当大人烂透了
I hear you. Being a grown-up sucks.
有那么多责任
You got all these responsibilities,
不能去追逐梦想了
and you just stop chasing your dreams.
你以为我喜欢同时做15份工作吗？
You think I like having 15 hustles?
嘿，等等，等等
Wait, wait, wait. Hold up, hold up.
冷静
Let's just calm down.
我想它只是需要被照顾下
I think this one just needs some TLC.
对吗？你喜欢骨头吗？
Yeah? You like bones?
你一定喜欢骨头，没错
Oh, I bet you like bones. Yes, you do. Yes, you do.
你好漂亮
Aren't you a beautiful one?
你好乖哦
-Yes you are! Yes you are! -
你居然驯服它了
I cannot believe you just did that.
等等
Wait.
（丹尼斯）
丹尼斯？
Dennis?
史蒂夫的丹尼斯？
-Steve's Dennis?
你能带我们去找他吗？
Well, can you take us to him?
小娜，这应该就是去林地府邸的路
Nat, I think this might be our way to the Woodland Mansion.
跟着它出发吧
Let's follow that pooch!
皇天不负有心人，终于到了
Son of a biscuit, we found it.
看看这里
Looky, looky here.
欢迎来到红石矿山
Welcome to the Redstone Mines.
看到发光的东西了吗？那就是红石
You see that glowy stuff? That's redstone.
可以传导能量
Conducts energy.
也能用来制造疯狂的装置
You can build some crazy contraptions with it.
你明明说这是钻石矿场
I thought you said this was a diamond mine.
别急，就在这里，但要小心
Easy, big dog. They're here, but be careful.
我很久以前设了一些陷阱
I set some booby traps a long time ago.
但我怎么也想不起来在哪了
But I can't for the life of me remember where they are--
帮我弄下来
Get them off me!
帮帮我
Help me, please!
抱歉
-Sorry!
找到了，谢了，加雷特
Hah! Here it is! Thanks, Garrett.
好耶
Yeah.
没错
Yes!
我的钻石
My diamonds.
总算是没白来
Ooh! That's what I'm talkin' about.
史蒂夫的财宝
Steve delivers the goodies!
这是你们的计划吗？
Did you guys plan this?
抱歉，亨利
I'm sorry, Henry.
我可不抱歉
Yeah! I'm not.
噢耶
Oh, yeah.
-你有没有搞错 -别激动
-What the heck, man? -Oh, relax.
娜塔莉往林地府邸去了
Natalie could be at the Mansion already.
她可能有危险
She could be in danger!
糟了，你们闻到了吗？
Oh, no. Do you smell that?
下界疣
Nether wart.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
不好，是霸王猪灵
No! The Great Hog!
他终于把脑子装上了
She finally put the brain in.
快上矿车
Run for the minecarts!
拉拉杆，亨利，快
Hit it, Henry, hit it!
我们走
Go!
我没记错的话，前面就有我建的超厉害避难所
If memory serves, I built a kick-ass safe room just up ahead.
可恶，火把灭了
Dang it, my torch blew out.
怎么停了？
Why are we stopping?
因为红石用完了
'Cause we ran out of redstone!
需要一个人下去推矿车
We're gonna need a boost fast.
什么声音？
What's that sound?
别害怕，加雷特，我们很安全
Chill out, Gar-Gar. We're totally safe.
坏了，是我的苦力怕农场
Crap! My creeper farm.
什么，你是不是脑子进水了
What the--? You gotta be kidding me!
谁没事会养这种鬼东西？
What kind of idiot would breed these things?
前面，你们看
-Up ahead, look! -
我们得把矿车推到红石轨道上
We gotta get to the redstone rail!
加雷特，这都是你害的
Garrett, you got us into this mess!
快下去推车
Get out and push!
好吧好吧
Okay. Okay.
快点，加雷特，再快点
Go, Garrett! Go faster!
我们逃不掉了
We're not gonna make it!
快点
Come on!
加把劲，加雷特，再快点
Come on, Garrett, you gotta go faster!
亨利，把它们锤开
Start slapping, Hank!
滚开
Get outta here! Yeah! Get--
加雷特，上车
-Garrett, get in! -
他要追上来了
He's right behind us!
我爱你，丹尼斯
I love you, Dennis!
喔吼~ 耶
Whoo-hoo! Yeah!
干得好，加雷特
Nice work, Gar-Gar.
非要来这，差点害死我们
Your little detour almost got us killed.
得了，少胡扯了，不是没事吗
Relaje, you're so dramatic. We're still alive.
你这人怎么回事？
What's your problem, man?
我们根本不需要那些破钻石
We didn't need those stupid diamonds.
我发誓，你绝对是见过的最自私的人
I swear, you are literally the most selfish person I've ever met.
我真的很需要那些钻石，好吗？
Whatever. I need them, okay?
我需要钻石，因为我身无分文
I need the diamonds, because I need the money, because I'm broke.
你不会懂的
You wouldn't know anything about that.
我的生活糟透了，我是个废物，行了吧
My life sucks, kid. All right? I'm a frickin' loser.
好了，我说出来了
There, I said it.
看起来我好像一切都好
I know it looks like I got it all put together, right?
我聪明、风趣，还会说两种语言
I'm smart, funny, bilingual.
我还非常谦虚
El humble to un el faultot.
但现实很无奈
But that's not the reality.
我过得不好
I'm not doing well.
我过气了，亨利，我即将一无所有
I'm washed up, Hank, and I'm gonna lose everything.
而这还不是最糟糕的
And that's not the worst part.
我孤身一人
I'm alone.
你不是
You weren't alone.
我当过你的朋友
I was your friend.
很遗憾你变成了穷光蛋
Sorry about your finances.
闭嘴，史蒂夫
Shut up, Steve.
天啊
Wow.
你还很擅长倾听
I feel like you get me, and you're an incredible listener.
只有情商高的人才会是好的倾听者
And only people with emotional intelligence are good listeners.
我真没想到
You know, I just didn't think it was in the cards
我以为我这辈子再也没有机会跟别人约会了
that I would have another first date, ever, you know?
我想鼓起勇气邀请你来我家吃甜点
I wanna have the guts to invite you over to my house for dessert.
您用完了吗？
Are you finished?
他应该是瑞典人
No, I think he's Swedish.
我们用完了
But we're done with our meal.
就是那里，林地府邸
There it is. The Woodland Mansion.
我们要进去，拿到魔力结晶
We're gonna get in there, get the Earth Crystal
然后送你们回家
and get you guys home.
跟我来
Follow me!
看好了
Check this out.
我来演示
Let's do this.
仔细看史蒂夫大师的战略
Pay close attention to Papa Steve.
林地府邸有三层
The Woodland Mansion has three floors.
第一层到处是卫道士
The first floor is loaded with Vindicators.
也就是斧头杀手
Axe murderers, basically.
为什么三楼放在一楼？
Why is the third floor on the first floor?
我搞糊涂了
I'm very confused.
我也想要摆成三层楼
I was trying to make three floors,
但现在没有时间搞大工程
but I didn't have time to make, like, a doll house.
然后是第二层，挤满了唤魔者
The second floor crawls with Evokers.
他们会用强大的黑魔法
They wield powerful dark magic.
我从没见过这么烂的模型
This is the worst model I've ever seen.
加雷特，你别找茬了，我们研究计划呢
Garrett, stop talking. We're trying to figure out a plan.
老弟，你到底要生气多久？
Bro, how long are you gonna be mad at me for?
我才刚开始生气
I just got mad at you.
跟你说件事，别生气，好吗
Please don't be mad at me for this, okay?
你造东西的时候，我偷走了这颗球
But I accidentally stole the Orb while you were crafting.
我们和好吧？
Are we cool now?
你简直就是整个世界最最差劲的人
You are literally the worst person in the entire world.
行了，你们两个，快仔细看我的演示
Guys! Both of you, eyes on my demonstraysh!
第三层，有个宝物储藏室
Third floor houses the Loot Chamber.
魔力结晶就在那儿
That's where the Earth Crystal is,
不过，那里有末影人看守
but it's guarded by Endermen.
无论发生什么，都不要直视他们的眼睛
Whatever you do, do not look them in the eye.
他们会扰乱你的脑袋
They'll fry your brains out.
好的，我造个楼梯爬到二层
Okay well, I could build stairs to the second floor,
从窗户溜进去，偷走魔力结晶
sneak in through the window, and snag the Earth Crystal.
这个主意不错
That's a great idea, Hank.
但我们需要想办法引开敌人的注意力
But to pull it off, we're gonna need a pretty sweet diversion.
我想到一个办法
You know what could work on these guys?
有一点疯狂
It sounds crazy.
说来听听
Hit me.
♪ 许下愿望，美好友谊♪
♪ Friendship is The wish you make ♪
♪ 一口气吹灭蛋糕蜡烛♪
♪ When you're blowing out The candles On your birthday cake ♪
♪ 别恃强凌弱，别横行霸道♪
♪ Don't be a bully And don't be a brute ♪
♪ 穿上你的生日礼服♪
♪ Time to put on ♪ - ♪ Your birthday suit ♪
♪ 去吧，亨利，赶紧去，趁着我们吹小曲♪
♪ Go Hank, go While we blow! ♪
这得找到什么时候
You gotta be kidding me.
你能行的，加雷特
You got this, Gar-Gar.
豁出去了
Reach down deep.
你是查格拉斯的骄傲，我爱你
You're the Chuglass Kid, and I love ya!
史蒂夫，他们要干嘛？
What's going on, Steve?
这是凶残的卫道士搏击俱乐部
It's some kind of sadistic Vindicator fight club.
我还是第一次亲眼见到
I've heard of these, but I've never seen one.
我要跟一只鸡打？
They want me to fight the chicken?
别松懈，这是生死之战
It's a fight to the death, kid.
鸡骑士
Chicken jockey.
小心
Watch out!
把他甩开
Keep him away from your face!
扔开他
Chuck him!
总算找到了
Finally.
抱歉，小朋友
I'm sorry, little buddy.
别上他当，加雷特
Don't fall for it, Gar-Gar!
这个小家伙可是心狠手辣的恶魔
That baby's got the heart of a demon!
你不是恶魔吧？
No, you're not a demon, are ya?
你只是个萌萌的小可爱
You're a cute little booger-face.
让我摸摸你的头
I'm just gonna… pet your little head.
你永远不会像我这么酷，亨利
You'll never be as cool as me, Hank.
放弃吧
Just give up.
主世界不需要你，亨利
The Overworld doesn't need you, Henry.
-我也不需要你 -放弃吧
-Neither do I. - Give up.
全是你的错，亨利，你老是搞砸一切
This is all your fault, Henry. Everything you do fails.
这玩意，就是垃圾
This stuff? It's trash, kid.
怎么回事
What the…?
加雷特! 不!
Garrett! No!
我来了
I'm coming!
等等
Hang on!
看我偷袭!
Sneak attack!
好样的，我来帮你，加雷特
Heck yeah. I got you, Gar-Gar.
起来
-Come on.
你救了我一命
You… You saved my life.
这是朋友该做的，加雷特
That's what friends do, Garrett.
亨利，你拿到魔力结晶了吗？
Hank! Did you get the Earth Crystal?
拿到了
Yeah, I got it.
我们该撤退了
Let's get outta this hellhole.
快点，快跑
Come on! Run!
我就知道你们这些笨蛋在这
I knew I'd find you dummies here.
不好，她来了
Oh no. It's her!
当然是我了，你这个笨蛋
Of course it's me, you fool.
我在两个生物群系外就开始追踪到你的气味了
I've been tracking your scent from two biomes away.
快来瞧瞧，我还做了新的霸王猪灵
Check it out. I even built me a new Hog.
马戈尔莎，你的统治结束了
Malgosha! Your reign is over!
恰恰相反
You're wrong.
我的统治才刚刚开始
It's just beginning.
不要
No!
可恶
杀了他们
Kill them.
我们还有正事要干
We have work to do.
永别了，史蒂夫
Goodbye, Steve!
不妙
No!
他们要炸飞这座桥
They're gonna blow this bridge sky high!
-抱歉，亨利 -什么？
-Sorry, Hank. -What?
正好，粘液块
Yeah! Slime cube.
上来，加雷特，快跳
Come on, Garrett, jump!
不行，史蒂夫
I can't, Steve.
带他逃出去
Get him outta here!
快走，亨利，去救你姐姐回家吧
Go, Hank! Save your sister and get home!
加雷特，别逞英雄
Garrett, you don't have to do this!
别忘了给我写首歌
Tell my story in song.
要重金属，重摇滚，别用电子乐
Keep it metal. Keep it heavy. Real instruments.
再说
Besides…
我最喜欢烤猪了
I love luaus.
回旋踢
Spin kick.
垃圾投掷
Garbage toss! Oh, crap!
不要
No!
我们要坠毁了
We're going down!
做好准备
Brace for impact!
丹尼斯？
-Dennis?
丹尼斯
-Dennis!
是你，真的是你
It's you! It's really you!
来个亲亲
Gimme…
你怎么找到我的？
How'd you find me?
这狼真棒
He's one heck of a wolf.
他带我们找到了你
He led us right to you guys.
现在我知道你为什么把自己弄得又脏又臭了
Now I understand why you kept yourself so filthy and smelly,
这样丹尼斯才能找到你
so Dennis could find you one day.
他没事吧？
Is he okay?
没事，只是在休息
He's fine. He's just resting.
太好了
Good.
迫降挺惊险的
It was a pretty rough crash landing.
等一下，我们在哪？
Wait a minute. Where are we?
哇塞
Whoa!
真希望垃圾侠能看到这个
I wish Garbage Man was here to see this.
他一定会很爱你的蘑菇小屋
He would've loved your mushroom hut.
是啊，我也这么觉得
Yeah, I think so too.
我好怕会失去你
I was so afraid that I lost you.
我也好怕会失去你
I was so afraid that I lost you, too.
对不起 我对你说了气话
I am really sorry about what I said.
加雷特的事我也很抱歉
And I'm really sorry about Garrett.
我只说一次
I'm only gonna say this once.
这个东西要放在那个东西上面
This thingy goes on top of that thingy.
明白了吗，特拉维斯？
Got it, Travis?
这会搞出一条炫酷的激光束，能遮住…
It's gonna make a real cool laser beam that'll darken--
算了
Never mind.
完了，完蛋了
No. No!
永夜降临了
The Great Darkening! It's begun.
马戈尔莎在集结所有兵力
Malgosha's gathering all her forces.
她会毁掉这片土地的
She will destroy this land.
除非我们抢回支配之球
Unless… we go get that Orb.
那我们在这干嘛呢？
Well, what're we doing here?
去干掉几只猪吧
Let's go fight some pigs.
我准备好了，我真是受够那些猪了
I'm ready. I'm done with those pigs.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
为了加雷特而战
Let's do it for Gar-Gar.
先挖矿，再合成
First we mine, then we craft.
一起守卫我的世界！
Let's Minecraft!
-1、2、3 -合作无间
- One, two, three. -Team!
-去拿球 -球，你刚才说什么？
-Get the Orb! -Orb! What are you saying?
-我的世界 -我们应该一起喊
-Minecraft. -We should all say that.
倒数3、1…算了，没时间啦
On three. One-- Forget it. There's no time!
亨利，该你上场了
Show us what you got, Henry.
好，我有个计划
Okay. I got a plan.
这配方简直是大杀器
Killer recipes.
我们要动作快
We're gonna have to move fast.
开始干活吧
Let's get to work!
首先，我们需要几块铁锭
First we're gonna need some iron ingots.
好耶
Oh, yeah!
还有迅捷之靴
And the boots of Swiftness.
是时候来点光亮了
Time to light this place up.
来吧，伙计们
Come on, boys.
炸飞你们
Have a nice flight!
你好棒
I bet you do. I bet you do!
还需要一堆钻石
We're also gonna need a ton of diamonds.
换你露一手了，小娜
Show me what you got, Nat.
好唉
Whoa! Yeah!
想挑战我？
You want some, buddy?
我们准备好了
We're ready.
一起拯救主世界吧
Let's go save the Overworld!
好啦，猪灵们
All right, my piggies.
今天，我们要占领主世界
Today, we take the Overworld as ours!
攻击村庄
Attack their villages.
烧毁他们的家园和那些对称的农场
Burn their homes and their symmetrical farms.
摧毁他们创造的一切
All they have created, we destroy!
你们还在这磨蹭什么？
Well, what are you standing around for?
快去啊
Get out of here!
快去，带回来黄金
Go on, bring me the gold!
快点，亨利
Hurry, Henry!
你们真蠢
Hah! News flash!
如果不挑衅铁傀儡，它们是不会攻击我们的
Iron Golems will not attack unless provoked.
你真厉害啊，特拉维斯
Real smooth, Travis!
准备好了吗？
You ready?
开始吧
Let's do this.
噢，真是服了
Oh, for goodness' sake!
蠢猪，你愣着干吗？
Well, what are you doing, you big block of meat?
快点下去，解决掉那群圆脑袋
Get down there and take care of those Roundlings!
怎么样？喜欢吗？
How do you like them pork chops?
快点
Come on!
马戈尔莎，一决胜负吧
Okay, Goshe. Let's dance.
放马过来
Bring it on.
看我偷袭
Sneak attack!
我的钻石盔甲
My diamond armor!
鸡蛋攻击!
Egg attack!
接招
-Frizz!
这是早餐自助吗？
What is this, breakfast?
放开我
Get off of me!
快，支配之球就在上面
Hurry! The Orb's up there!
去吧，亨利
Do it, Henry.
我自己能行的
I got this.
快去，亨利，快去
Go, Henry, go!
大块头
Hey, Captain Butt Crack!
我给你带礼物了
I got something for you.
拿下他，丹尼斯
Get him, Dennis.
喔吼! 吃猪肉啦!
Whoo! Take a bite outta that pig!
快点，亨利
Finish this, Henry!
-亨利 -不要
-Henry! -No!
不要
No!
我抓住你了，小子
Gotcha, kid!
-好耶 -噢耶
- Yes! -Yes!
太好了
Yes!
加雷特，你还活着
Garrett, you're alive!
当然咯
Yeah!
偷偷告诉你，我用了史蒂夫的落地水
Between us, I used Steve's water bucket trick.
很酷吧
Pretty cool, huh?
是有点啦
Little bit.
去拿支配之球，我们回家咯
Let's get this Orb and go home.
好耶，加油，亨利
Yes! Yes, go, Henry!
预备，亨利，火球时间
All right, Hank. It's fireball time.
用那把长矛
Grab that spear.
猛戳上面的触毛
I want you to jab it in the tentacles.
好耶
-Yeah.
哇哦! 用力戳
Whoo! Jab it!
好耶
Yeah!
你从哪学会这一招的？
How'd you learn how to do that?
别问我
Don't ask.
好耶
Yeah!
不要
No!
你干了什么好事？
What have you done?
支配之球！
The Orb!
好耶
Yes!
见到你真好，垃圾侠
It's good to see you, Garbage Man.
没错
Yeah, it is.
格挡，进攻
Parry! Thrust!
你输了，女巫
You failed, witch.
主世界得救了
The Overworld lives on.
这也输了，这根本不是胜利
You, too, have fallen for the great lie.
你永远也不会快乐
You'll never be happy.
你的打心底就明白
Deep down, you know.
希望、梦想、创造，毫无乐趣可言
To hope, to dream, to create is to suffer.
你说得对
You're right.
创造总比破坏难
It is harder to create than to destroy.
这就是为什么懦者才会选择后者
That's why cowards tend to choose the deuce.
后会有期，女巫
Later, Goshe.
跟你交手真是浪费大家时间
Every minute knowing you has been a horror-show waste of time.
别走，还有一件事
Wait, one more thing.
靠近点
Come closer.
你是藏着小刀想刺我吗？
Do you have a little knife that you're gonna try to stab me with?
没有，我太虚弱了
No, no. I'm too weak.
好吧
All right.
真是够了
Come on!
总得试试嘛
It was worth a shot.
等等，再听我说一件事
Wait, wait. Let me say one more thing.
-靠近点 -少来
-Come closer. -No way!
真的，跟你有关
No, really, it's about you.
好吧
Fine.
靠过来
Lean down here.
你烂透了
You really are the worst.
慢走不送
Goodbye.
这次不骗人了，回来
This is it, really. Come back.
我没刀了
I don't even have a knife.
我没得藏了
Where would I keep it?
看我偷袭
Sneak attack.
等等
Hey!
你确定要回去吗，亨利？
You sure you wanna go back, Henry?
跟这里不同
It won't feel like this.
你会处处受限，被嘲笑，障碍重重
There you got constraints, judgments, obstacles.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
但我还是会发挥创意的
But I'm gonna go make stuff anyway.
我喜欢这点
I like that.
你是个勇敢的孩子
You're a brave kid.
史蒂夫，你确定不一起吗？
Steve. You still cool with this?
对
Yeah.
过来，孩子
Come here, boy. Yeah.
我当然还爱你
Of course I still love you.
所以我觉得这是个好主意
That's why I think this is a good idea.
你改变了我的人生
-You changed my life. -
是时候去改变她的了
It's time for you to go change hers, too.
♪去吧，丹尼斯♪
♪ Go now, Dennis ♪
♪改变道恩的人生，丹尼斯♪
♪ Change Dawn's life, Dennis ♪
♪去踏上旅途吧♪
♪ Go on a journey ♪
♪别忘了记着我，丹尼斯♪
♪ And think of me, Dennis ♪
♪去吧，我梦中的传奇之狼♪
♪ Go now, legendary Wolf of my dreams ♪
♪我的小狼狼♪
♪ My doggie, doggie, doggie ♪
♪我的丹尼斯♪
♪ My Dennis ♪
要是早知道你能唱得这么好听
If I would have known you could sing like that,
我或许就能忍受你的气味了
it would have helped me get past your smell.
加雷特
Garrett…
你真是个英勇无畏的战士
you are a truly bodacious warrior…
也是个好朋友
and a really good friend.
真希望你能跟我们回家
I wish you'd come home with us.
亨利很酷
Hank's cool,
但我没有同龄的朋友
but I don't have any friends my age.
我们组队能强强联手
We would make a great team.
（西班牙语）“老天保佑你”
Vaya con Dios.
意思是“再会，兄弟”
It means "Goodbye, brother."
才不是
No, it doesn't.
别看她
Don't look at her.
是真的
It does.
才不是
No, it does not.
真的是
Yeah, it does.
你确定不回去吗？
Are you sure you don't want to come back?
对，我要留在这里
Yeah, I'm staying here.
我还想建造好多东西
I got a bunch more stuff I wanna build.
为什么不把那种魔力带到现实世界来呢？
Why don't you bring some of that magic to the real world?
不管了，我也跟你们走
Screw it, I'm coming with.
事实证明，只要你足够勇敢，就能把现实世界
Turns out, if you're brave enough, you can make the real world…
变成你的主世界
…your Overworld.
（主世界）
加雷特终于升级了
Garrett finally leveled up.
他的店现在人来人往
And his store became the hot spot!
我们一起齐心协力打造了新的热门游戏
Together, we all joined forces to create the new hit game,
“方块城市战斗伙伴”
Block City Battle Buddies.
方块城市战斗伙伴
Block City Battle Buddies!
当然，我们还在测试阶段
Yeah, we're still in the beta phase,
要解决一些漏洞
working out a few bugs.
但我承认，生活其实... 挺美好的
But let me tell ya, life…is pretty perfect.
♪耶 耶♪
♪ Yeah, yeah! ♪
♪我曾于童年醒来 嬉戏玩耍♪
♪ I used to wake up and play Back in my childhood days ♪
♪长大成人 真是可耻至极♪
♪ Gettin' older's Such a dirty shame ♪
♪我从未有过机会 让想象力尽情飞舞♪
♪ They never gave me a chance To let my imagination dance ♪
♪直到我创造出 不同的游戏♪
♪ 'Til I came up With a different game ♪
♪终日矿洞 劳作不息♪
♪ Down in the mines All of the time ♪
♪创造不停♪
♪ Crafting ♪
♪阳光之下 欢声笑语♪
♪ Out in the sun Havin' some fun ♪
♪开怀大笑♪
♪ Laughing ♪
♪我永不会回头 因为♪
♪ I'm never, ever Lookin' back, 'cause ♪
♪我感到鲜活♪
♪ I feel alive ♪
♪耶♪
♪ Yeah ♪
道恩终于辞掉了房地产的工作
Dawn finally got to ditch her real estate job.
玩的开心
Have fun!
她和丹尼斯去到哪，欢乐就在哪
She and Dennis brought the party wherever they went.
（丹尼斯）
娜塔莉决定在现实世界传授她的新技能
Natalie decided to share her new skill set with the real world.
自卫生存模式
Survival Mode Self-Defense.
接着他会…
And now he's going to--
查格拉斯的治安变得超级好
The streets of Chuglass have never been safer.
你好强，娜塔莉
You get 'em, Natalie!
那亨利呢？
And Henry?
他的喷射背包终于成功了
He finally got that jetpack to work.
（查格拉斯中学）
♪我感到鲜活♪
♪ I feel alive ♪
♪我用意志移山♪
♪ I move mountains With my mind ♪
♪我感到高昂♪
♪ I feel the high ♪
♪如新月升起♪
♪ Like a new moon on the rise ♪
♪我感到鲜活♪
♪ I feel alive ♪
♪仿佛红石过载♪
♪ Like a redstone overdrive ♪
♪我感到鲜活♪
♪ I feel the high ♪
♪体内狼力 奔涌向前♪
♪ With the power Of the wolf inside ♪
♪我感到鲜活♪
♪ I feel alive ♪
♪耶♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
（副校长玛琳）
我知道你最爱吃面包了
I know how much you love bread.
玛琳，你的前夫来了
Marlene, your ex-husband's here.
他说有急事找你
He said it was an emergency.
好吧，你告诉他，我跟他没什么好说的
Well, you tell him I've got nothing to say to him.
你不是开玩笑吧，你找了他？
You gotta be kidding me, Marlene. This is the guy?
太迟了，克莱门特
Too late, Clemente.
我给过你机会的
You had your chance.
她说得对，克莱门特，你自己搞砸了
She's right, Clemente. You totally blew it.
事到如今，你的错误造就了我的幸福
And now I reap the rewards of your mistake.
当初，玛琳开着大切诺基把我撞飞的时候
You see, when Marlene's Jeep Grand Cherokee ran me over,
我的内心也被爱情之箭射中了
I was struck by a love so powerful,
是爱情让我们
it transcended the barriers
轻松跨越了语言的鸿沟
of conventional speech.
我现在学会了人类语言，她也学会了村民语
Now I speak Human, and she speaks Villager.
当撞到你的那一刻，我就知道你是我的真命天子
The moment I hit you with my car, I knew you were the one.
我也是
Me too!
哦，亲爱的，原来你也有同样的感觉
Oh my darling, you feel the same way...
玛琳，自从昨晚我们相遇
Marlene, ever since we met last night,
我就一直想说
I wanted to say,
你愿意嫁给我吗？
"Would you marry me?"
我愿意，千千万万次愿意
Yes! Yes! A thousand times, yes!
（我的世界大电影）
嗨，抱歉打扰了
Hi, sorry to bug. I just--
我以前住在这里，我是史蒂夫
I used to live here, and-- I'm Steve.
你是来拿阁楼上那个箱子的吗？
Oh, is this about that chest in the attic?
对，幸好还在
yeah! I'm so glad that's still around.
嘿，请进来吧
Hey, you want to come in?
我叫艾莉克丝
I'm Alex, by the way.
艾莉克丝，很高兴认识你
Alex, great to meetch.